彼得·艾伦·泰勒是我父亲
Peter Alan Tyler, my dad.
他是世界上最棒的人
The most wonderful man in the world.
生于1954年9月15日
Born 15th September, 1954.
过来 洛斯 过来吧
Come here, Rose. Come here.
这是谁呀 -这是你爸爸
Who's that? - It's your daddy.
他去世的时候你还太小 应该不记得了
You weren't old enough to remember when he died.
1987年11月7日
1987, 7th November.
你记得我是怎么告诉你的吗
Do you remember what I told you?
就在斯图尔特·霍斯金斯
The day that Stuart Hoskins
和萨拉·克拉克结婚那一天
and Sarah Clark got married.
他总是喜欢去冒险
He was always having adventures.
他要是能看到现在的你一定会很高兴
He would have loved to have seen you now.
妈妈经常会这么说
That's what Mum always says.
所以我在想 我们…
So I was thinking, could we...
我们能不能回到我爸爸还活着的时候
could we go and see my dad when he was still alive?
你这是心血来潮吗
Where's this come from all of a sudden?
好吧 如果不行的话
All right, if we can't,
如果这违反了什么时空规则
if it goes against the laws of time or something,
那就算了 不用管了
then never mind, just leave it.
不 我什么都能做 我只是更担心你
No, I can do anything. I'm just more worried about you.
我想见他
I want to see him.
谨遵所命 但你要小心你所许的愿望
Your wish is my command. But be careful what you wish for.
神秘博士第一季第八集
父亲节
我 彼得·艾伦·泰勒
I, Peter Alan Tyler,
愿意娶杰奎琳·安德列·苏泽特·普兰提斯
take you, Jacqueline Andrea Suzette Prentice.
我 彼得·艾伦·泰勒
I, Peter Alan Tyler,
愿意娶杰奎琳…
take you, Jacqueline...
苏泽…苏西…
Susanne, Suzette...
安妮塔
Anita?
继续吧 没叫我狄姑娘已经很不错了
Just carry on. It's good enough for Lady Di.
我还以为他会更高点
I thought he'd be taller.
作为我的合法妻子
To be my lawful wedded wife.
相亲相爱相互扶持 唯有死亡能将我们分开
To love and behold till death us do part.
他死在我们家附近
He died so close to home.
我当时不在场 没人在场
I wasn't there. Nobody was.
那是一起肇事逃逸
It was a hit-and-run driver.
一直没找到肇事者
Never found out who.
救护车到的时候他已经咽气了
He was dead when the ambulance got there.
我只希望当时有人能陪着他
I only wish there'd been someone there for him.
我想陪着他 他就不用孤独地死去了
I want to be that someone. So he doesn't die alone.
11月7日吗 -1987年
November 7th? - 1987.
太诡异了
It's so weird.
今天我父亲死了
The day my father died.
我还以为一整天都会阴沉沉的
I thought it'd be all sort of grim and stormy.
但其实不过是普通的一天
It's just an ordinary day.
过去这里是另一个国家
The past is another country.
1987年这里就是怀特岛郡
1987 is just the Isle of Wight.
你确定要去吗 -是啊
You sure about this? - Yeah.
就是这里 乔丹路
This is it. Jordan Road.
他迟到了
He was late.
他是去拿结婚礼物的 一个花瓶
He'd been to get a wedding present, a vase.
妈妈经常说 "那该死的花瓶"
Mum always said, "That stupid vase".
他下了车
He got out of his car...
然后过马路
and crossed the road.
天呐 就是这里
Oh, God, this is it.
去看看他 快点
Go to him. Quick.
现在太晚了
It's too late now.
救护车来之前 他就死了
By the time the ambulance got there, he was dead.
他不能就这样一个人死去
He can't die on his own.
我能再试试吗
Can I try again?
这是之前的我和你
Right, that's the first you and me.
这是个坏主意 同时出现了两对我们
It's a very bad idea, two sets of us being here at the same time.
小心点 别让他们看到我们
Just be careful they don't see us.
等到她跑开然后他跟过去时 去找你爸爸
Wait till she runs off and he follows then go to your dad.
天呐 就是这里
Oh, God, this is it.
我做不到
I can't do this.
如果你不想的话不必强求
You don't have to do anything you don't want to.
但这是我们最后一次机会
But this is the last time we can be here.
洛斯 不
Rose, no!
我做到了 我救了你的命
I did it. I saved your life.
天呐 他开得多快 你记下车牌号了吗
Blimey, did you see the speed of it? Did you get his number?
我真的成功了 天呐 你还活着
I really did it. Oh, my God, look at you, you're alive.
那辆车差点撞死你
That car was gonna kill you.
相信我 我看到他开过来了
Give me some credit, I did see it coming.
我又没打算撞过去 对吧
I wasn't gonna walk under it, was I?
我是洛斯
I'm Rose.
真巧 我女儿也叫这个名字
That's a coincidence. That's my daughter's name.
那是个好名字 这个选择不错
That's a great name. Good choice. Well done.
我得快点了 还得去参加婚礼
Right. I better shift. I've got a wedding to go to.
是萨拉·克拉克的婚礼吗
Is that Sarah Clark's wedding?
是的 你也去吗
Yeah. Are you going?
是啊
Yeah.
要我搭你和你男朋友一程吗
Do you and your boyfriend need a lift?
进来吧 不好意思这么乱
Right, there we go, sorry about the mess.
如果想喝茶的话
If you want a cup of tea,
厨房在那边 牛奶在冰箱里
kitchen's down there, milk's in the fridge.
不过牛奶除了放冰箱里还能放哪
It would be, wouldn't it? Where else would you put the milk?
不过呢 还是可以放在窗台上的
Mind you, there's always the windowsill outside.
我一直在想
I always thought
如果有人发明了一种特殊的窗台牛奶箱
if someone invented a windowsill with special compartments,
一边放牛奶 一边放酸奶
one for milk, one for yoghurt,
准能赚好多钱 专门卖给学生之类的
make a lot of money out of that. Sell it to students and things.
我应该记下来
I should write that down.
别介意 不好意思 我得去换个衣服
Anyway, never mind that. Excuse me, I got to go and change.
这都是他的东西 妈妈都收起来了
All the stuff mum kept. His stuff.
她把这些东西都打包塞到碗橱里去了
She kept it all packed away in boxes in the cupboard.
她喝了点酒就会拿出来给我看
She used to show me when she'd had a bit to drink.
现在都摆在外面
Here it is, on display.
摆在原来的位置上
Where it should be.
保龄球第三名 第两名可以去迪德科特
Third prize at the bowling. First two got to go to Didcot.
养生饮料
Health drinks.
我妈经常说是开胃水
Tonics Mum used to call them.
他就靠卖这些花草饮料赚钱
He made his money selling this Vitex stuff.
他干过各种活 他很聪明
He had all sorts of jobs, he was so clever.
太阳能 妈妈说他本来是准备做这个的
Solar power. Mum said he was going to do this.
现在他能如愿以偿了
Now he can.
好了 我会告诉他你不是我男朋友的
Okay, I'll tell him you're not my boyfriend.
我们见面时我说"和我一起在宇宙中旅行吧"
When we met I said, "Travel with me in space".
你拒绝了我
You said, "No".
然后我说"时光机器"
Then I said, "time machine".
这不是什么策划已久的计划
It wasn't some big plan.
我只是看着这一切然后想"我能阻止"
I just saw it happening, and I thought, "I can stop it".
我又这样 又挑了个愚蠢的原始人旅伴
I did it again. I picked another stupid ape.
我就知道
I should have known.
你根本不是想畅游宇宙 根本不是
It's not about showing you the universe. It never is.
你是为了利用宇宙
It's about the universe doing something for you.
所以只准你自己穿越时空
So it's okay when you go to other times
去拯救别人吗
and you save people's lives
我救我父亲就不行吗
but not when it's me saving my dad?
我知道我在干什么 你不知道
I know what I'm doing, you don't.
两对我们同时出现会让那段空间变得很不稳定
Two sets of us being there made that a vulnerable point.
但他还活着
But he's alive.
我的星球毁灭了 还有我的家人
My entire planet died, my whole family.
你以为我从没想过回到过去拯救他们吗
Do you think it never occurred to me to go back and save them?
但我又没改变什么历史
But it's not like I've changed history.
我是说没改变多少
Not much. I mean,
他又不会成为什么世界领袖
he's never gonna be a world leader,
他也不会挑起第三次世界大战
he's not gonna start World War III.
洛斯 有个原本应该死去的人现在还活着
Rose, there's a man alive in the world who wasn't alive before.
普通人 正是这个自然界中最重要的存在
An ordinary man. That's the most important thing in creation.
整个世界都会因为他而发生改变
The whole world's different because he's alive.
所以你更希望他死吗 -我不是说…
Would you rather him dead? - I'm not saying that...
不 我懂了
No, I get it.
现在你不是我生命中最重要的人了
For once, you're not the most important man in my life.
咱们看看没了我之后你怎么办 把钥匙给我
Let's see how you get on without me. Give me the key.
塔迪斯的钥匙
The TARDIS key.
如果我这么不重要 还给我
If I'm so insignificant, give it me back.
那好 还给你
All right then, I will.
你现在得到你想要的结果了 再见
You've got what you wanted so that's goodbye, then.
你吓不到我
You don't scare me.
我知道你很难过 你过一会就会回来
I know how sad you are. You'll be back in a minute.
或者你会在塔迪斯外面晃悠等着我
Or you'll hang around outside the TARDIS waiting for me.
我会让你等很久很久
And I'll make you wait a long time.
跟男朋友吵架了吗
Boyfriend trouble?
不好意思 你在整理什么
Excuse me, do you mind? What are you tidying up for?
不好意思 习惯了
Sorry, force of habit.
别为他烦心 小两口就是会吵架的
Don't worry about him. Couples have rows all the time.
我们不是一对 为什么大家都觉我们是一对
We're not a couple. Why does everyone think we're a couple?
我觉得他离开我了 -你这么靓的妹子
I think he left me. - What? A pretty girl like you?
换我肯定会… -打住
I was going out with you... - Stop right there.
我只是说…
I'm just saying...
我知道你要说什么 还是别往那方面想吧
I know what you're saying and we're not going there.
我们根本不能往那方面想
At no point are we going anywhere near there.
你根本不知道那方面是哪方面…
You aren't even aware that there exists...
我不想去想那方面的事
I don't want to think about there and,
相信我 你也不想
believe me, neither do you.
那方面对你来说
There, for you, is like...
跟百慕大三角一样
like the Bermuda Triangle.
天呐 你可真会哄人开心 -我们走吗
Blimey, you know how to flatter a bloke. - Right. Are we off?
你这就不会让人误会了吗 -当然不会
That wouldn't be a mixed signal at all? - Absolutely not.
我还是把你送回疯人院去吧
I'll take you back to the loony bin where you belong.
不过我相信好像在哪见过你
Except I'm sure I've met you somewhere before.
真奇怪 -什么
It's weird. - What?
好多人都不见了
There's so many people missing.
史蒂芬叔叔 琳恩阿姨 巴克斯特家的人
Uncle Steven, Auntie Lynn, all the Baxters.
他们都去哪了
Where are they?
你不觉得有点不对劲吗
You don't think something's gone wrong?
也许这是天赐的良机让你能好好考虑考虑
Maybe it's a godsend, gives you time to think.
你不用完成婚礼的 这年头不在乎这个了
You don't have to go through with it, not these days.
偶尔也放纵一下嘛 -爸爸
Live in sin for a bit. - Dad.
十年之内你就会说
In 10 years' time, you'll turn round and say,
"要是能让时光倒流就好了"
"If only I could turn the clock back."
是我的问题还是真的变冷了
Is it me or did it just get cold?
洛斯
Rose.
我在赛马场碰到这家伙
I met this bloke at the horses
他分了我点版税
and he's cutting me in on copyright.
但我以为你是个正经的生意人
But I thought you were a proper businessman.
我也想啊 我什么都干一点 养家糊口
I wish. I do a bit of this, bit of that. I scrape by.
好吧 肯定是我听错了
Right. I must've heard wrong.
所以其实你有点打肿脸充胖子
So, really, you're a bit of a Del Boy.
你还真说对了
Shoot me down in flames.
你不会碰巧认识我太太吧
You're not related to my wife by any chance, are you?
天呐 她也会去婚礼
Oh, my God. She's gonna be at the wedding.
杰琪 你认识她吗
Jackie? Do you know her?
算是吧
Sort of.
那她跟你谈过我吗
What's she told you about me, then?
她说她嫁给了世上最棒的男人
She said she'd picked the most fantastic man in the world.
那肯定是另一个杰琪 她从没这么说过
Must be a different Jackie, then. She'd never say that.
这种音乐听得我头疼
This stuff goes right over my head.
这歌应该还没出呢吧 -没出就好了
That's not out yet. - Good job and all.
我得看看短信 -什么叫短信
I'm just gonna check my messages. - How do you mean? Messages?
这是电话吗 -是啊
Is that a phone? - Yeah.
华生 过来 我需要你
Watson, come here. I need you.
半数客人没出现
Half the guests haven't turned up.
你最好别过来 简直是一场灾难
You're better off not being here, it's a disaster in the making.
不 我看这就是"未婚先孕"
No, in this case, "Knocked her up" is a phrase I'd use.
华生 过来 我需要你
Watson, come here. I need you.
你好 你是谁
Hello? Who's this?
华生 过来 我需要…
Watson, come here. I...
爸爸 快进来 不能在婚礼前看到新娘
Dad, get inside. We can't see the bride before the wedding.
会带来厄运的 -你遇到她就是厄运
That's bad luck. - Bad luck when you met her.
我告诉你 今天是被诅咒的一天
I tell you, this day is cursed.
这才叫蛋糕裙嘛
Now that's what I call a meringue.
斯图尔特的爸爸都打算走人了
Stuart's dad said go round the block
因为人们都不见了
'Cause there's people missing.
什么叫不见了
How do you mean, missing?
戴夫没来 苏尼塔没来 比尔没来
There's no Dave, no Sunita, no Bee...
羊旗俱乐部的人也没来
There's no one from The Lamb and Flag.
我的拖尾又裂开了 我就应该用魔术贴的
My train's detached again. I knew I should have used Velcro.
有我呢 别发牢骚了
I'm here, stop your bellyaching.
帮我照顾一下洛斯好吗
Take Rose a sec, will you?
她可真漂亮
Ain't she pretty?
她是个小淑女 这才像话嘛
She's a little madam, that's what she is.
我需要人来帮个忙
I need more hands.
她那个没用的爸爸到哪去了
Where's her useless article of a dad got to?
爸爸
Dad!
就是那辆车 就是之前那辆
It's that car. Same one as before.
就在眼前的 跑哪去了
It was right in front of us, where's he gone?
你叫我爸爸 你为什么这么叫我
You called me "Dad"? What did you say that for?
太棒了 他来了 等着他又闯祸吧
Oh, wonderful! Here he is, the accident waiting to happen.
就你这样估计连自己的葬礼都会迟到
You'd be late for your own funeral and it nearly was.
又没误事 -这是谁
No damage done. - And who's this?
你张着嘴巴看什么呢
What are you looking at with your mouth open?
你的头发 -什么
Your hair. - What?
我从来没见过…
I've never seen it like...
我是说…
I mean...
很漂亮 你的头发很漂亮
it's lovely, your hair's lovely.
还有你抱着的宝宝
And that baby you're holding.
那是你的宝宝吗
That would be your baby.
又是你的某个马子吗 -她救了我的命
Another one of yours, is she? - She saved my life.
这个理由挺新鲜的啊 上次是什么来着
That's a new one. What was it last time?
我又不认识她 她就是个衣帽间的服务员
I didn't even know her. She was a cloakroom attendant.
我是在帮她找我的票
I was helping her look for my ticket.
那边有三件一模一样的粗呢大衣
There were three duffle coats all the same.
不知道为什么那个衣架突然倒了
Somehow the rack collapsed.
我们都被压在下面
We were under all this stuff.
你是在到处沾花惹草吗
Were you playing around?
他干什么关你什么事
What's it got to do with you what he gets up to?
他到底干了什么 -你自己知道
What does he get up to? - You'd know.
我会蠢到这种地步
Because I'm that stupid.
带自己的情人来见老婆吗
I play around and I bring her to meet the missus.
你这个蠢婆娘 -你就是那么蠢
You silly cow. - But you are that stupid.
咱们能回家再说吗 暂时别吵了
Can we keep this stuff for back home, just for now?
回家跟你那堆垃圾一起吗
What, with the rest of the rubbish?
你把廉价清洁剂 开胃水和贝塔录像机
You bring home cut-price detergents, tonic water,
都搬回了家 结果没一个卖得出去
Betamax tapes and none of it works.
我都快被你的垃圾淹没了
I'm drowning in your rubbish.
他怎么和你说的 是不是说他是个大商人
What did he tell you? Did he say he's this big businessman?
他才不是 他是个失败者 天生的失败者
'Cause he's not. He's a failure. Born failure, that one.
洛斯需要一个好爸爸
Rose needs a proper father...
杰琪 我在赚钱养活我们呢
Jackie, I'm making a living. It keeps us fed, doesn't it?
住嘴
Stop it.
你们不是这样的 你们爱着对方
You're not like this. You love each other.
彼得 你不是不喜欢别人神经质兮兮的吗
Pete, you never used to like them mental.
我也不知道 说不定你还真喜欢
Or I don't know, maybe you did.
要是你不小心… -杰琪 等等
If you're not careful... -- Jackie, wait, listen...
别人结婚之日就是你离婚之日
there'll be a wedding and a divorce on the same day.
等等 让我和我太太好好谈谈
Wait here. Give us a couple of minutes with the missus.
这样吧 把车挨着街角停好
Tell you what, straighten the car up. Stick it round the corner.
别再惹什么乱子了
Don't cause any more trouble.
杰克
Hey, Jack.
我不听 肯定又是上次衣帽间事件重演
I'm not listening. It's the duffle coats all over again.
杰琪 有时候毛呢大衣真的只是毛呢大衣
Jackie, sometimes a duffle coat is just a duffle coat.
一切都会好起来的 我保证
Things will get better soon. I promise.
我受够你那些不靠谱的雄心壮志了
I've had enough of all your daft schemes.
我吃了上顿都不知道有没有下顿
I never know where the next meal's coming from.
我会搞定的 亲爱的 很快的
I'll get it right, love. One day soon,
我保证我会让我们好起来
I promise you I'll get it right.
来吧
Come on.
怪兽 怪兽要吃我们
Monsters! Going to eat us!
什么怪兽 亲爱的 是外星人吗
What sort of monsters, sweetheart? Is it aliens?
洛斯
Rose!
到教堂里去
Get in the church!
天呐 那是什么
Oh, my God. What are they?
进去
Inside!
萨拉 -待着别动
Sarah! - Stay in there!
都进去
In!
他们进不来 这种老式的门窗没问题
They can't get in. Old windows and doors. Okay.
越古老越坚固
The older something is, the stronger it is.
还有什么
What else?
去看看别的门 快点
Go and check the other doors. Move!
怎么回事 它们是什么东西
What's happening? What are they? What are they?
时间出问题了 出现了伤痕
There's been an accident in time. A wound in time.
它们就像是趁虚而入的病菌
They're like bacteria, taking advantage.
什么时间 你在胡说些什么
What do you mean? Time? What are you jabbering on about time?
我应该想到你会跟我吵
I might've known you'd argue.
杰琪我受够你了 -你怎么知道我的名字
Jackie, I'm sick of you complaining. - How do you know my name?
我没空跟你扯了 -我这辈子从没见过你
I don't have time for this! - I've never met you in my life.
要是我不解决这事 你还真见不到我了
No, and you never will unless I sort this out.
如果你不介意的话 我已经忍了很久了
Now if you don't mind, I've waited a long time to say this,
杰琪·泰勒 照我说的做 去检查那些门
Jackie Tyler, do as I say. Go and check the doors.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
我早就该这么做的
I should've done that ages ago.
我爸爸在外面 -你可以迟点再哀悼
My dad was out there. - You can mourn him later.
你现在得集中注意力 让我们一起活下来
Now we've got to concentrate on keeping ourselves alive.
我爸爸… -我也无能为力
My dad had... - There is nothing I can do for him.
不 但是他有这个电话
No, but he had this phone thing.
我没法修好 但是一直有这个声音
I can't get it to work. I keep getting this voice.
华生 过来 我需要你
Watson, come here. I need you.
这是世界上第一通电话
That's the very first phone call.
亚历山大·格拉汉姆·贝尔
Alexander Graham Bell.
我觉得电话应该没什么用
I don't think the telephone's gonna be much use.
我们总得报警
Someone must have called the police.
现在警察帮不了你 没人能帮你
The police can't help you now, no one can.
宇宙中没人能伤到它们
Nothing in this universe can harm those things.
时间出现了裂口 它们是来给伤口消毒的
Time's been damaged and they've come to sterilise the wound.
它们要抹杀所有的东西
By consuming everything inside.
这是因为…
Is this because...
这是我的错吗
Is this my fault?
不
No!
城里一些地方在冒烟 但是没有火警
There's smoke coming up from the city. But no sirens.
我觉得不只是我们
I don't think it's just us.
我觉得这些东西到处都是
I think these things are all over the place.
可能全世界都是
Maybe the whole world.
那是一辆车吗
Was that a car?
这不重要 不要担心
It's not important. Don't worry about it.
你的那个伙伴 什么叫这是你的错
This mate of yours. What did he mean, this is your fault?
不知道 这一切吧
Don't know. Just everything.
我把我的车钥匙给了你
I gave you my car keys.
我一般不会把钥匙给陌生人
You don't give your keys to a complete stranger.
好像我很信任你
It's like I trusted you.
我见到你那一刻就信任你
The moment I met you, I just did.
时间的伤痕
A wound in time.
你叫我爸爸
You called me Dad.
我看得出来
I can see it.
你有我的眼睛
My eyes.
还有杰琪的态度
Jackie's attitude.
你大喊的时候就像她一样
You sound like her when you shout.
你是 你是 你是我的洛斯
You are. You are. You're my Rose.
你是我长大后的洛斯
You're my Rose, grown up.
爸爸 我的爸爸 我的爸爸
Dad! My dad. My daddy.
不好意思
Excuse me.
您是… -博士
Mister? - Doctor.
你好像知道发生了什么事
You seem to know what's going on.
的确如此
I give that impression, yeah.
我只想问… -你能救我们吗
I just wanted to ask... - Can you save us?
你们俩是谁
Who are you two, then?
斯图尔特·霍斯金斯 -萨拉·克拉克
Stuart Hoskins. - Sarah Clark.
还有一个呢 男孩还是女孩
And one extra? Boy or girl?
我不知道 我也不想知道
I don't know. I don't want to know, really.
这一切是怎么开始的
How did all this get started?
动感酒吧外 凌晨两点
Outside the Beatbox Club, 2:00 in the morning.
街角 我钱包丢了 没钱打车
Street corner, I'd lost my purse, didn't have money for a taxi.
我把她带回了家 -然后呢
I took her home. - Then what?
让她跟你去约会吗
Asked her for a date?
把号码写在我手上
Wrote his number on the back of my hand.
然后再也甩不掉她了
Never got rid of her since.
我爸爸说…
My dad said...
我不知道这是怎么回事
I don't know what this is all about
我知道我们无足轻重…
and I know we're not important...
谁说你们无足轻重
Who said you're not important?
我去过各种各样的地方
I've travelled to all sorts of places,
干过很多你们无法想象的事
done things you couldn't even imagine.
但是你们俩
But you two.
凌晨两点在街角打的回家
Street corner, 2:00 in the morning, getting a taxi home.
我从来没经历过
I've never had a life like that.
没错
Yes.
我会尽力救你们的
I'll try and save you.
我是个爸爸
I'm a dad.
我是说 我已经是爸爸了
I mean, I'm already a dad
但是洛斯长大后变成你这样
but Rose grows up and she's you.
太棒了
That's wonderful.
我是说我还以为你不会有这么厉害
I mean, I suppose I thought that you'd be a bit useless
因为有我的废物基因什么的…
what with my useless genes and all but...
你是怎么来这里的
Well, I mean, how did you get here?
你真的想知道吗 -是啊
Do you really want to know? - Yeah.
时光机
A time machine.
时光机 -我发誓
Time machine? - Cross my heart.
你那个时候大家都有时光机了吗
Do you all have time machines where you come from?
不 只有博士有
No, just the Doctor.
你知道会出现这些东西吗
Did you know these things were coming?
不知道
No.
天呐 我不知道 我脑子里一片浆糊
God, I don't know, my head's spinning.
未来是怎么样的
What's the future like?
没什么不一样
It's not so different.
我怎么样 头发白了吗
What am I like? Have I gone grey?
我秃了吗 别告诉我我秃了
Have I gone bald? Don't tell me I've gone bald.
如果这家伙不是你的男朋友
So, if this mate of yours isn't your boyfriend,
我想说我还是很欣慰的
and I have to say I'm glad
因为作为你的父亲 我觉得他有点太老了
'cause being your dad and all, I think he's a bit old for you.
你有男朋友吗 -没有 曾经有过
Have you got a bloke? - No. I did have.
米奇
Mickey.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
穿着西服我还真认不出来
I just didn't recognise him in a suit.
你得放开我 亲爱的
You have to let go of me, sweetheart.
我总是这么说
I'm always saying that.
这孩子看到什么就跟宝贝一样抱住
He just grabs hold of what's passing and holds on for dear life.
要是他以后有女朋友了 那姑娘还真可怜
God help his poor girlfriend if he ever gets one.
我和洛斯只是在聊天 -聊天是吗
Me and Rose were just talking. - Oh, yeah? Talking?
当世界要毁灭时 你在干什么
While the world comes to an end, what do you do?
黏着某个年轻的金发妞
Cling to the youngest blonde.
走吧 米奇
Come on, Mick.
你不能告诉她 -为什么
You can't tell her. - Why?
我是说我不希望你告诉她
I mean, I really don't want you to tell her.
你不希望让别人知道吗 -我那个时候
You don't want people to know? - Where I come from,
杰琪连播放器的时间条都搞不定
Jackie doesn't know how to work the timer on the video recorder.
我上礼拜才教过她
I showed her that last week.
我懂了
Point taken.
洛斯 你才不会
Rose, you're not going to
让世界毁灭的 对不对
bring about the end of the world, are you?
对不对
Are you?
杰琪让我照顾她
Jackie gave her to me to look after.
真是时过境迁啊
How times change.
我还是小心点吧
I'd better be careful.
我刚刚给米奇留下了鸡妈妈一样的印象
I think I just imprinted myself on Mickey like a mother chicken.
不 别碰宝宝
No. Don't touch the baby.
你们是同一个人 这是悖论
You're both the same person, that's a paradox.
我们不希望发生悖论 外面还有这些东西
We don't want a paradox happening, not with these things outside.
时间的任何扰动都会增强它们的力量
Anything new, any disturbance in time, makes them stronger.
悖论甚至可能把它们放进来
A paradox might let them in.
我什么都做不对 对吗
I can't do anything right, can I?
你都这么问了 没错 所以别碰宝宝
Since you asked, no. So, don't touch the baby.
我又不笨 -你别想骗我
I'm not stupid. - You could have fooled me.
好吧
All right...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我没打算真的扔下你一个人
I wasn't really gonna leave you on your own.
我知道
I know.
实话告诉你 我毫无头绪 完全没有
Between you and me, I haven't got a plan. No idea.
不知道怎么办
No way out.
你会想出来的
You'll think of something.
整个地球都受到了侵蚀
The entire Earth's been sterilised.
这里 还有其他地方
This, and other places like it,
全人类就只剩下这几个人了
are all that's left of the human race.
我们可能还能撑一会
We might hold out for a while,
但是根本挡不住这些东西
but nothing can stop those creatures.
它们还是会闯进来 这些墙不够古老
They'll get through in the end. The walls aren't that old.
我也没法阻止它们
And there's nothing I can do to stop them.
本来有阻止这类事态的法则
There used to be laws stopping this kind of thing from happening.
我的族人本来能阻止这一切
My people would have stopped this.
但他们都不在了
But they're all gone.
现在我也要随他们而去了
And now I'm going the same way.
要是我知道…
If I'd realised...
只要
Just...
告诉我你很抱歉
tell me you're sorry.
是的
I am.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎么有东西在发热
Have you got something hot?
是塔迪斯的钥匙
It's the TARDIS key.
这说明钥匙还跟塔迪斯连着呢
It's telling me it's still connected to the TARDIS.
我的飞船的内部被甩到了时间伤痕之外
The inside of my ship was thrown out of the wound
但是我们能用这个找回来
but we can use this to bring it back.
只要我把飞船找回来 就能修复好一切
And once I've got my ship back, then I can mend everything.
我现在只需要一点电 你们谁有电池吗
Now, I just need a bit of power. Has anybody got a battery?
这个够大了吗
This one big enough?
妙极了
Fantastic.
好老爹 拿着
Good old Dad. There you go.
只需要稍微充个电
Just need to do a bit of charging up.
然后我们就能把大家带回来了
And then we can bring everyone back.
你还没说你为什么要来这里呢
You, erm, you never said why you came here in the first place.
要是我有个时光机器
If I had a time machine,
我不会觉得1987年有什么特别的
I wouldn't have thought 1987 was anything special.
至少这附近没啥特别的
Not round here, anyway.
我们只是碰巧 -我真幸运啊
We just ended up here. - Lucky for me, eh?
要是你没有救我
If you hadn't been there to save me...
那只是个巧合
That was just a coincidence.
那真的只是运气好 太棒了
That was just really good luck. It's amazing.
那在未来 我和她还生活在一起吗
So, in the future, are me and her indoors still together?
是啊
Yeah.
你还和我们住在一起吗 -是啊
You still living with us? - Yep.
我是个好爸爸吗
Am I a good dad?
你…
You...
我小时候你每天都会给我讲睡前故事
You told me a bedtime story every night when I was small.
你每晚都会来 从来不会错过
You were always there, you never missed one.
然后…
And, erm...
你每周六都会带我们去乡间野餐
you took us for picnics in the country every Saturday.
你从来不会让我们失望
You never let us down.
你一直陪伴着我们
You were there for us all the time.
你是个值得依赖的父亲
Someone I could really rely on.
那不是我
That's not me.
好了 所有人都不准碰那把钥匙
Right, no one touches that key,
听懂了没 不准碰
have you got that? Don't touch it.
要是有人碰 就会啪的一下消失
Anyone touches that key, it'll be, well, zap!
不要碰它 一切都会没事的
Just leave it be and everything will be fine.
我们大家都会逃出去
We'll get out. All of us.
斯图尔特 萨拉 你俩能结婚了
Stuart, Sarah, you're gonna get married, just like I said.
当时间回到原样…
When time gets sorted out...
大家都会忘记发生了什么
Everybody here forgets what happened.
别担心 你改变的事情还是会保持下去
And don't worry, the thing that you changed will stay changed.
你是说我会活下去吗
You mean I'll still be alive.
虽然我应该死了
Though I'm meant to be dead.
所以我这一生中什么都没干
That's why I haven't done anything with my life.
所以这一生毫无意义
Why it didn't mean anything.
不是那样的 -扯吧
Doesn't work like that. - Rubbish.
我太没用了 死都死不好
I was so useless I couldn't even die properly.
现在发生这一切都是我的错
Now it's my fault all this has happened.
这是我的错 -不 亲爱的
This is my fault. - No, love.
我是你爸爸
I'm your dad.
这就是我的错 我的职责
It's my job for it to be my fault.
她的父亲 你怎么会是她的父亲
Her dad? How are you her dad?
你几岁生的她 十二岁吗
How old were you? 12?
太恶心了 -杰琪 听着
Oh, that's disgusting. - Jacks, listen.
这是洛斯 -洛斯
This is Rose. - Rose?
太变态了
How sick is that?
你竟然给咱们的女儿起了个二手名字
Did you give my daughter a second-hand name?
到底有几个 你都叫他们洛斯吗
How many are there? Do you call them all Rose?
看在上帝的分上 这就是洛斯
Oh, for God's sake, look. It's the same Rose.
洛斯 不
Rose, no!
大家都躲到我后面来
Everyone, behind me!
我是这里最老的人
I'm the oldest thing in here.
博士
Doctor!
冷的
It's cold.
钥匙是冷的
The key's cold.
天呐 他死了
Oh, my God, he's dead.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
你们俩 你们所有人
Both of you, all of you.
这个世界
The whole world.
就这样了 我们完了 结束了
This is it. There's nothing we can do. It's the end.
博士真的很在乎你
The Doctor really cared about you.
他不想让你再经历一次伤痛
He didn't want you to go through it again.
总想尝试另外的办法
Not if there was another way.
现在别无选择了
Now there isn't.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
那辆本应杀死我的车 亲爱的
The car that should have killed me, love.
就在这儿
It's here.
博士早就发现了 但是他…
The Doctor worked it out way back but he...
他想保护我
tried to protect me.
但是
Still.
现在已经不是他说了算了
He's not in charge anymore.
而是我
I am.
你不能这样 -我是谁 亲爱的
But you can't. - Who am I, love?
我的爸爸
My daddy.
杰琪 看看她
Jackie, look at her.
她是我们的女儿
She's ours.
上帝啊
Oh, God.
我注定要死 杰琪
I'm meant to be dead, Jackie.
你终于要摆脱我了
You're gonna get rid of me at last.
不要这么说
Don't say that.
这辈子就信我这一次 必须要这样
For once in your life, trust me. It's got to be done.
你得活下去 因为你得养大我们的女儿
You've got to survive 'cause you've got to bring up our daughter.
我从来没给你讲过睡前故事
I never read you those bedtime stories,
我也从来没带你去过野餐
I never took you on those picnics.
我从来没有陪过你
I was never there for you.
你本应跟我们一起
You would've been.
但我可以为你做这件事
But I can do this for you.
我现在可以做你的好爸爸
I can be a proper dad to you now.
但这样不公平
But it's not fair.
我还多活了这么久
I've had all these extra hours.
世界上没人有过这种待遇
No one else in the world has ever had that.
除此之外 我还见到了你
And on top of that, I get to see you.
你这么美丽
And you're beautiful.
我是多么幸运啊
How lucky am I, eh?
来吧 乖乖听爸爸的话
So, come on. Do as your dad says.
你会陪着我吗 亲爱的
You gonna be there for me, love?
谢谢你救了我
Thanks for saving me.
再见 亲爱的
Goodbye, love.
去看看他吧 快点
Go to him. Quick.
那司机只是个孩子
The driver was just a kid.
他停下来等着警察
He stopped, he waited for the police.
这不是他的错
It wasn't his fault.
不知道为什么 彼得突然冲出来
For some reason, Pete just ran out.
人们说有个女孩
People say there was this girl.
彼得死前她陪在他的身边
And she sat with Pete while he was dying.
她牵着他的手
She held his hand.
然后她走了
Then she was gone.
谁也不知道她是谁
Never found out who she was.
彼得·艾伦·泰勒 我爸爸
Peter Alan Tyler, my dad.
这个世界上最棒的人
The most wonderful man in the world.
死于1987年11月7日
Died 7th November, 1987.
下集预告
那我们追它做什么
And why are we chasing it?
因为是它淡紫色级别的危险啊
It's mauve and dangerous,
而且再过30秒就要撞到伦敦市中心了
and about 30 seconds from the centre of London.
洛斯
Rose!
求你放我进来 妈咪
Please let me in, Mummy.
别让他碰到你
You mustn't let him touch you.
你是医生吗 -当过一阵子
Are you a doctor? - I have my moments.
他们的伤势完全相同
They've all got the same injuries.
连手背上的伤疤都一样
Right down to the scar on the back of the hand.
虽是皮肉伤 却如瘟疫般传播
Physical injuries as plague.
你好 -你好
Hello. - Hello.
到阳台上喝一杯吧
Shall we have a drink on the balcony?
我倒觉得自己更像个罪犯 -我也这么觉得
I like to think of myself as a criminal. - I bet you do.